(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
進め！BAKATARATION
Forward! BAKATARATION
作詞：真崎エリカ　作曲：多田彰文 (Arte Refact)
編曲：脇 眞富 (Arte Refact)
Forward! BAKATARATION
Lyrics: Erika Masaki / Composition: Akifumi Tada (Arte Refact)
Arrangement: Masatomi Waki (Arte Refact)
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
新しい時代進んでく私たち
We're advancing into a new era
「みんなで進む～！」
“Let's all move forward~!”
朝まで騒ごう 夜更かしは悪くないよね？
Let's party 'til morning, staying up late isn't bad, right?
「悪くないよね？」
“It's not bad, right?”
世界揺らがせるくらい強い絆のなかで
Within a bond strong enough to shake the world
ハイになってGo!
Get high and go!
Oh yeah!
尻尾振ってGo!
Wag your tail and go!
Oh yeah!
3, 2, 1, バカタレーション！
3, 2, 1, BAKATARATION!
楽しんじゃえ Delight!
Let's enjoy it Delight!
聞かせてよね Satelight!
Let us hear it Satelight!
今夜もそうノリをまけテンションで
Tonight as well, let the rhythm spread in high tension
私たちがナンバーワン！
We are number one!
いつだってオンリーワン！
Always only one!
これまでもさあこれからも
Just as before, and from now on
ワクワクは続いてくよ！
The excitement will continue!
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
初めての扉さあドンドン開けていこう
Let's keep opening new doors one after another
「怖がらずに行こ〜！」
“Let's go without fear~!”
ついついやさぐれでも一人じゃない…よね？
Even when feeling down, we're not alone... right?
「一人じゃない…よね？」
“We're not alone... right?”
迷ってもいいよ だって寄り道もイベントだし
It's okay to get lost, 'cause even detours are part of the event
前のめりGo!
Lean forward and go!
Oh yeah!
助走つけGo!
Take a run-up and go!
Oh yeah!
まだまだバカタレーション！
The BAKATARATION is still going!
駆け抜けてこう Always!
Let's run through it Always!
はしゃぎながら All days!
While having fun All days!
ノリノリでノリでまけ大混乱
Spreading chaos with high-energy vibes
地球は広いけどまるっと一周
The Earth is vast, but let's go all the way around
シアワセで侵略出来そう
It feels like we can conquer it with happiness
ドタバタは続いてくよ！
The slapstick fun will continue!
今日のみんな、バカタレ2周年のライブだー！
Today everyone, it's Bakatare's 2nd Anniversary Live!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ということでね、ここでちょっと意気込みを一人ずつ言ってみよう。
So, let's each say a little something about our enthusiasm here.
じゃあまずはわためから。
Okay, let's start with Watame.
はい！
Yes!
バカタレらしいライブをするので、みんな付いてきてね！
We're going to put on a very "Bakatare" live, so everyone, stay with us!
イエーイ！
Yay!
次はフレア！
Next is Flare!
はーい！
Yes!
ついにこの日がやってきました！バカタレのみんなと盛り上がるから、みんなも付いてきてね！
This day has finally come! I'm going to have a blast with all of Bakatare, so everyone, come along with us!
イエーイ！
Yay!
そして最後にフブキング！
And finally, Fubuki-ng!
はい！
Yes!
今日はみんなで楽しむぞ！よろしくなー！
We're all going to have fun today! Nice to meet you!
イエーイ！
Yay!
遊び足りない日はもう少し一緒に
On days when we haven't played enough, let's stay together a bit longer
もっともっと一緒に
More and more together
みんなでときめこう無敵な友情
Let's all feel the excitement of our invincible friendship
未来へと振りかざして
Brandishing it toward the future
さあ、進め！BAKATARATION
Now, forward! BAKATARATION
楽しんじゃえ Delight!
Let's enjoy it Delight!
聞かせてよね Satelight!
Let us hear it Satelight!
今夜もそうノリをまけテンションで
Tonight as well, let the rhythm spread in high tension
私たちがナンバーワン！
We are number one!
いつだってオンリーワン！
Always only one!
これまでもさあこれからも
Just as before, and from now on
ワクワクは続いてくよ！
The excitement will continue!
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ゴー！
Go!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
作詞：藤林聖子　作曲：佐橋俊彦
Seijuu Sentai Gingaman
Lyrics: Shoko Fujibayashi / Composition: Toshihiko Sahashi
走れ 地球狭しと 駆け巡れ
Run, run across the Earth as if it's too small
ギンガマン
Gingaman
闇を揺さぶる　風になれ　ギンガマン
Shake the darkness, become the wind, Gingaman!
吠えろ　吠えろ　吠えろ　ギンガマン
Roar, roar, roar, Gingaman!
大地をつかむ足音を聞け
Listen to the footsteps gripping the earth.
強く　激しく　誰よりも高く
Strongly, intensely, higher than anyone.
沈む太陽　引き上げるのさ　ギンガマン
You'll pull up the sinking sun, Gingaman.
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
五つの叫び　とどろかせ
Make five cries resound.
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
銀河をつらぬく伝説の刃
The legendary blade that pierces the galaxy.
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai Gingaman
バカタレ
Bakatare
走れ　星も光も追い越して　ギンガマン
Run, overtaking even the stars and light, Gingaman!
走れ　闇を切り裂く虹になれ　ギンガマン
Run, become a rainbow that cuts through the darkness, Gingaman!
吠えろ　吠えろ　吠えろ　ギンガマン
Roar, roar, roar, Gingaman!
嵐を目指す瞳をくれ
Give me eyes that gaze into the storm.
強く　優しく　誰よりも熱く
Strongly, kindly, more passionately than anyone.
燃える太陽　信じてるのさ　ギンガマン
Believing in the burning sun, Gingaman.
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
五つの願いを胸に秘め
Keeping five wishes hidden in your heart.
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
銀河をつらぬく伝説の刃
The legendary blade that pierces the galaxy.
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai Gingaman
バカタレ
Bakatare
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
五つの叫び　とどろかせ
Make five cries resound.
ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン　ガンガンギギン　ギンガマン
Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman! Gan Gan Gi Gin, Gingaman!
銀河をつらぬく伝説の刃
The legendary blade that pierces the galaxy.
星獣戦隊ギンガマン
Seijuu Sentai Gingaman
バカタレ
Bakatare
はーい！ということでですね、始まりました、BAKATARATION PARTY、イエーイ！
Hi! So, BAKATARATION PARTY has officially begun! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
どうも高い位置から失礼いたします
Sorry for addressing you from such a high position.
失礼いたします
Excuse us!
馬に乗らせていただきまして、なんか走ってましたね、この子可愛い
We're riding horses, and they were actually running. This one's so cute.
ね
Right?
よしよしよしよし。…あれ、わためぇのそれ羊？
There, there. ...Wait, Watame, is that a sheep?
羊じゃない？
Isn't it a sheep?
いや、馬だよ！
No, it's a horse!
馬か！
A horse, huh!
羊じゃないよ！
It's not a sheep!
馬か！
A horse!
カッコいいでしょ！
Doesn't it look cool?
あ、これ、あ、なんか草食べてる、草食べてる
Oh, look. Ah, it's eating grass. It's eating grass.
草食べてる、大丈夫か？
It's eating grass. Is it okay?
元気出してね、草食べて元気出して。
Cheer up, okay? Eat grass and feel better.
ということでですね、1曲目は『進め！バカタレ！』さんでしたー！
So, the first song was 'Advance! Bakatare!'
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい！潔い！なんかダンスをちらっと間違えた人がいたような気がするんですが…
Yes! How gallant! I feel like someone might have made a slight mistake in the dance...
はい！
Yes!
おお、潔い
Oh, how straightforward.
はい、間違えました。最後ね、あの、こうなんだけど、こうなっちゃった
Yes, I messed up. At the end, it was supposed to be like this, but I did this.
ああ、そうなってたね
Ah, you did do that.
で、わためぇもなんか…
And Watame, you also...
はい！
Yes!
本当はこうなのに、フブちゃんのほう向いておてて繋ぎに行っちゃった
I was supposed to do this, but I turned to Fubuchan and tried to hold hands.
最後ね、おてて繋ぎに行っちゃったね
Yeah, you went to hold hands at the end.
そしてフブちゃんは？
And what about you, Fubuchan?
私はもう間違えるわけないですよ
There's no way I would ever make a mistake.
おおー！
Ooh!
間違えてなかったですよ！サビのダンス考えたの白上なんですから！
I didn't mess up! After all, I'm the one who choreographed the chorus dance!
じゃあ、そういうことにしときますか
Well, let's just go with that then.
ええー！？
Whaaat?!
あの、オープニングとかに馬が出てたので、ちょっと馬を用意していただきました！
Since horses appeared in the opening, we had them prepare some for us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
嬉しい、乗れて嬉しい。
I'm so happy I got to ride one.
ね、乗れてよかったね。降りることもできるけど、一切降りなかったね、二人とも。
Right, I'm glad. You can get off, but neither of you did at all.
かわいいから乗ってた。
We stayed on because they're cute.
ずっと乗ったままやんけと思って。
I was thinking, "You're just staying on them."
え、このMCずっとこのままですか？
Wait, are we staying like this for the whole MC?
降りる？でもまだ始まったばっかりで、他にも何回も、やるよね、MCね。
Should we get off? But it just started, and we'll have more MC segments, right?
確かに。おしゃべりしてると思うから、まあ最初は...
True. Since we'll just be chatting, for the start...
最初はのんびりと...
Let's take it easy at first...
是非この辺にテロップで、私たち名前のせといてください。
Please put our names in the captions around here.
ああ、やっぱりね。誰々です、誰々です、誰々です。
Ah, right. "I'm so-and-so," "I'm so-and-so," "I'm so-and-so."
そうそうそう、お願いします。
Yes, yes, yes. Please do.
この後もね、確かにMCもありますし、曲もね...
After this, we'll have more MC segments and songs...
いっぱい歌っていこうと思いますので、今日はよろしくお願いいたします！
We're going to sing lots of songs, so please enjoy the show today!
いっぱい盛り上がりましょう！
Let's get hyped!
わため、馬がちょっと歩いてるけど大丈夫か？
Watame, the horse is walking a bit, are you okay?
帰りたいんか、もしや。
Does it want to go home, maybe?
ダメダメ。帰りたいみたい。帰ろうとしてる。
No, no. It seems it wants to go home. It's trying to go back.
じゃあ、次の曲の準備をしに、じゃあ行きますか！
Then, shall we go get ready for the next song?
はーい！じゃあ次の曲もお楽しみに！
Okay! Look forward to the next song!
よいしょー！
Heave-ho!
馬なのに... そっちにこっちくんか...
Even though it's a horse... It's coming this way...
いくよ！
Here we go!
マミムメモヤモヤな君も Are you ready? 準備はいい？
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me-Moya-moya you too, are you ready? Are you prepared?
ステップアップで 1 2 3 はい！ ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム
Step up, 1, 2, 3, yes! Positive Dance Time
夢色を奏でるよ 空で Shall we dance?
Playing dream-colors in the sky, shall we dance?
明日に笑われるくらい
Enough to be laughed at by tomorrow
しかめ面 お月様も 一緒に Shall we dance?
Grimacing Mr. Moon, join us, shall we dance?
最高の気分で
In the best of moods
1 2 3 のリズムで
With the 1, 2, 3 rhythm
1 2 3 魔法をかけて
1, 2, 3, casting a spell
君だけのステップだから 世界がほら輝くの
Because it's your own step, look, the world shines
Wake up! Wake up! 遅れないでよ 魅惑のダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't be late, the captivating dance time
Jumping! Jumping! 恥ずかしがらずに ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイハイハイ！
Jumping! Jumping! Without being shy, high! high! high high high high!
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ パピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
嫌なことも ダメダメダメ！ 君と一緒に踊れば
Bad things are no good, no good, no good! If I dance with you
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ 今はぎこちないリズムでも
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Even if the rhythm is awkward right now
青空に Let's be ambitious! きっと輝くから
To the blue sky, let's be ambitious! It will surely shine
マミムメモのりのりな君も Are you ready? 準備はいい？
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me-Nori-nori you too, are you ready? Are you prepared?
ステップアップで 1 2 3 はい！ ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム
Step up, 1, 2, 3, yes! Positive Dance Time
雲色を奏でるよ 空で Shall we dance?
Playing cloud-colors in the sky, shall we dance?
昨日を笑い飛ばすくらい
Enough to laugh off yesterday
泣き虫な お星様も 一緒に Shall we dance?
Crybaby stars, join us, shall we dance?
笑顔にしちゃおうよ
Let's make them smile
1 2 3 のリズムで
With the 1, 2, 3 rhythm
1 2 3 魔法をかけて
1, 2, 3, casting a spell
君だけのステップだから 世界がほら輝いた
Because it's your own step, look, the world has shone
Wake up! Wake up! 止まらないでよ 素敵なダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't stop, the wonderful dance time
Jumping! Jumping! 無我夢中で ほら ハイ！ハイ！ハイイェー！
Jumping! Jumping! In a trance, look, high! high! high yeah!
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ パピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
前を向いて Let's! Let's! Let's! 君と一緒に奏でよう
Look forward, let's! let's! let's! Let's play together with you
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ 今は慣れないメロディでも
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Even if the melody is unfamiliar right now
夢色に Let's be ambitious! きっと届くから
In dream-colors, let's be ambitious! It will surely reach
準備はいいかー！
Are you ready?!
Wake up! Wake up! 遅れないでよ 超最高のダンスタイム
Wake up! Wake up! Don't be late, the super-best dance time
Jumping! Jumping! 思いのまま ほら ハイ！ハイ！ハイハイハイハイ！
Jumping! Jumping! As you wish, look, high! high! high high high high!
宝素晴らしい！ ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ パピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
Treasure-wonderful! Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
涙拭いて Let's! Let's! Let's! 君と一緒に踊れば
Wipe your tears, let's! let's! let's! If I dance with you
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ 今は真っ白なキャンバスも
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Even if the canvas is blank right now
君色に Let's be ambitious! 描けるの
In your color, let's be ambitious! You can paint it
もう一回！ ポジティブダンスタイム
One more time! Positive Dance Time
ダシダシタイ！ ダシダシタイ！ パピプペ ポジティブダンスタイム
Want to let it out! Want to let it out! Pa-Pi-Pu-Pe Positive Dance Time
みんなで派手 Let's! Let's! Let's! 楽しい楽しい優勝だね
Everyone flashy, let's! let's! let's! It's fun, fun victory
虹色の毎日を ずっとずっと 笑い疲れるくらい
Rainbow-colored every day, always and forever, enough to get tired of laughing
踊ってたい Let's be ambitious! でも今日はおやすみ
I want to keep dancing, let's be ambitious! But for today, good night
マミムメモヤモヤな君も...
Ma-Mi-Mu-Me-Moya-moya you too...
先にミミ Are You Ready? 準備はいい？
First, Mimi, Are You Ready? Are you prepared?
Shake and Clap
1, 2, 3, はい！
1, 2, 3, here we go!
ポジティブ☆ダンスタイム！
Positive Dance Time!
Cry Baby
作詞・作曲：藤原 聡
Lyrics & Composition: Satoshi Fujiwara
胸倉を掴まれて
Grabbed by the collar
強烈なパンチを
A powerful punch
食らってよろけて
Taking it and staggering
肩を並べ蹲った
Shoulder to shoulder, we crouched down
予報通りの雨に
In the rain just as forecasted
お前はニヤけて
You smirked
傷口が綺麗になるなんて
Saying wounds will become beautiful
嘘をつく
Is a lie you tell
いつも口喧嘩さえ
Even though when it's just a verbal spat
上手く出来ないくせして
You can't even handle that well
冴えない冗談
That dull joke
言うなよ
Don't say it
あまりのつまらなさに目が潤んだ
It was so boring it brought tears to my eyes
何度も青あざだらけで
Many times, covered in bruises
涙を流して 流して
Shedding tears, over and over
不安定な心を
Our unstable hearts
肩に預け合いながら
Leaning on each other's shoulders
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
We resist a rotten bad end
何故だろう 喜びよりも
I wonder why, more than joy
心地よい痛み ずっしりと響いて
A comfortable pain echoes heavily
濡れた服に舌打ちしながら
Clicking my tongue at my wet clothes
腫れ上がった顔 見合っては笑う
We look at each other's swollen faces and laugh
土砂降りの夜に
In the pouring rain of the night
誓ったリベンジ
We swore our revenge
胸倉を掴み返して
Grabbing back by the collar
反撃のパンチを
A counter-attack punch
繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ
If I can't at least throw that
お前の隣には立てないから
I can't stand by your side
相手が何であれ怯まない
No matter who the opponent is, I won't flinch
何度伸されても諦めない
No matter how many times I'm knocked down, I won't give up
忘れるな 忘れるなと 言い聞かせ続けたのに
Even though I kept telling myself, 'don't forget, don't forget'
どうして
Why?
食らいついて
Clinging on
信じて
Believing
どうして
Why?
どうして！
Why?!
あぁ 傘は要らないから
Ah, I don't need an umbrella
言葉を一つくれないか
Can't you give me just one word?
温い優しさではなく
Not a lukewarm kindness
弱音に侵された胸の奥を
But for the depths of my heart, tainted by weakness
抉るような言葉を
Words that gouge right through it
何度も青あざだらけで
Many times, covered in bruises
涙を流して 流して
Shedding tears, over and over
不安定な心を
Our unstable hearts
肩に預け合いながら
Leaning on each other's shoulders
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
We resist a rotten bad end
何故だろう 喜びよりも
I wonder why, more than joy
心地よい痛み ずっしりと響いて
A comfortable pain echoes heavily
濡れた服に舌打ちしながら
Clicking my tongue at my wet clothes
腫れ上がった顔 見合っては笑う
We look at each other's swollen faces and laugh
土砂降りの夜に
In the pouring rain of the night
囚われた日々に
In the days I was trapped
問いかけるように
As if asking a question
光った瞳の中で
Within my shining eyes
誓ったリベンジ
I swore my revenge
はい、ということで、あ、漫才組みたいになってます。どうも！
Yes, so, ah, we look like a comedy duo. Hello!
どうしてー！
Whyー!
どうして戦ったのー！
Why did we fight!
なんかね、なんかむしゃくしゃしたんだ。
I don't know, I just felt frustrated.
なんかちょっと…なんかちょっと気になったんだ。
I was a little... I was a little curious.
うん、そうするしかない気がしてさ。
Yeah, I felt like that was the only way.
気持ちよく歌ってたのにさ！
And I was singing so comfortably!
いやぁ、そうだよ。
Well, that's how it goes.
フレアと殴り合ったこの拳で…
With these fists that fought Flare...
いやぁ、ちょっと絆深めていた…イェーイ！
Yeah, we were deepening our bond... Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
バカタレってそういう感じなんだ。
So that's how Bakatare is.
そうだったよ、今更。
That's how it's always been.
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということでね、
And so,
ポジティブ☆ダンスタイムとCry Babyを聴いていただきました。
you've heard 'Positive Dance Time' and 'Cry Baby'.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
わー！
Wa-!
まずね、ポジティブダンスタイムなんですけども。
First off, regarding Positive Dance Time...
もうぐだぐだだったね。
It was totally messy, wasn't it?
ぐだぐだでしたね。
It really was messy.
歌に集中しすぎて、合わせようと思ってたところが全然ダンス合わなくて。
We focused too much on singing, and the parts where we meant to sync up, our dancing didn't match at all.
あのね、フブちゃん、私思ったの。
You know, Fubu-chan, I realized something.
なんだい？
What's that?
これさ…踊る曲じゃないわ。
This, you see... It's not a song for dancing!
ちょっとね、思ってた。思ってたけど、まあポジティブダンスタイムだけでも合わせようって言ったけど、ダメでした！
I kind of thought so too. I thought so, but I said let's at least sync for Positive Dance Time, but it didn't work!
あの、みんな切り抜く時はね、出来てるところ切り抜いてもらって。
Everyone, when you make clips, please only clip the parts where we got it right.
そうだね、そうだね。出来てるところね。
That's right, that's right. The successful parts.
ポジティブダンスタイム、一回だけ合ってるはず。
In Positive Dance Time, there should be one time where we matched.
合ってる。一回だけ出来てる。
We matched. We did it exactly once.
一回だけ合ってるの。
We matched just once.
そこだけ使ってね。
Please use only that part.
お願いします！
We're counting on you!
はい、そして乙女の…はい、出だしなんだよこれ。
Yes, and then 'Otome no...' wait, this is the intro.
かっこよかった！
That was cool!
強者でしたね。
You looked like a pro.
強者だった。
I was a pro.
勇者じゃないでしょ。
You're not a hero, are you?
でもリベンジするんでしょでも。
But you guys are going to have a revenge match, right?
そうね。
That's right.
強者だけどリベンジすんの。
You're pros, but you're doing a revenge match.
リベンジすんの。
We're doing a revenge match.
二人にな！二人にリベンジ！
To the two of you! A revenge match for the two of you!
嘘…二人にリベンジ！やるよね？
No way... a revenge match for the two of us! We'll do it, right?
あそこもかっこよかった。
That part was cool too.
よかっためちゃ。
It was really good.
気持ちよく歌ってたのにね、二人後ろで何やってたのかなぁ？
I was singing so comfortably, but I wonder what you two were doing behind me?
いや、だからほら、闘志がね、闘志が。そう。
No, well, you see, our fighting spirit... yeah.
みなぎっちゃった？
Was it overflowing?
みなぎってしまった。
It completely overflowed.
やっぱりね、戦いを求めてるね、我々。
As expected, we are seeking battle.
なるほど。
I see.
そういうこと。
That's how it is.
闘争心。
A fighting spirit.
闘争心、闘争心。体は闘争を求める。
Fighting spirit, fighting spirit. The body craves conflict.
このあとも闘争の曲いっぱいあるからね。
There are many battle songs coming up after this.
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
確かに確かに。このあともちょっとあの、熱いね。
True, true. The next ones are a bit... hot, aren't they?
ね。
Yeah.
あちちね。
Scorching.
あちち。
まだまだ二人には体力続く限り頑張ってもらいましょう！
We'll have these two keep working as long as their stamina lasts!
本当に結構今ので限界だったよフブちゃん大丈夫？
Honestly, I was pretty much at my limit just now, Fubu-chan, are you okay?
確かにちょっと…まだまだあるよ。
True, a little... There's still more.
歌ったあとに二人で「はぁ…！」
After singing, the two of us were like 'Phew...!'
うん。
Yeah.
そんなに大丈夫？
Are you that okay?
大丈夫。全然大丈夫だよ。
I'm okay. I'm totally okay.
さっき中から爆笑になってない大丈夫？
Weren't you laughing hysterically from the inside just now? Are you okay?
うん、今のとこ大丈夫。このあとから来るかもしれない。
Yeah, I'm okay for now. It might hit me after this.
ちなみに次の曲は？
By the way, what's the next song?
あれ？
Oh?
お、二人の？デュエット？
Oh, by the two of you? A duet?
お、かっこいいのやっちゃう？
Oh, are you gonna do a cool one?
やっちゃう。
We're doing it.
やっちゃうの？
You are?
ださくない？これ。
Isn't it a bit uncool? This.
ださくない。
It's not uncool.
それはちょっとださくない？
Isn't that a little uncool?
ださくない？ちょっととりあえず…
Not uncool? For now, let's...
急降下…こう殴り合いみたいな感じでいく？
A sudden exchange... shall we go with a vibe like punching each other?
あ、やっちゃう？
Ah, shall we?
もっともっと。
More and more.
逆に怖いですね。
That's scary in its own way.
じゃあまだそろそろお暇しておきましょうかね。
Well then, I should probably take my leave now.
ということでこのあとは二人のデュエットからです。
So, up next is a duet from these two.
ばーい！
Bye-!
かっこよく決めるででぞ。
I'll wrap it up coolly.
おけい！
Okay!
打ちつかれたこの鼓動は無力ではかないもの
This weary heartbeat is a powerless and fleeting thing
痛みは空よりも麗らかに
The pain is more serene than the sky
鬼薊 空が合う 風も熱も夢も明日も
Thistles, the sky meeting the wind, heat, dreams, and tomorrow
虚空中に彷徨った 理想 怒り 視線 刹那
Ideals, anger, gazes, moments wandering in the void
渦を巻くよう 哭く哭く深い場所
Deep places crying, crying like a swirling vortex
ジリジリ音を立てて絡め取られ
Sizzling sounds, then being mesmerized
数え切れぬ音の瞳が全部笑ったら 後ろの正面 その目は誰？
If all the countless eyes of sound laugh, who is that in front of the back?
まるで闇に描かれた 叶わぬ夢模様
Like a dream drawn in the darkness that will not come true
髪を振り乱すような気配がざわめく
A presence like disheveling hair is rustling
やがてそこに訪れた 両手に余る哀しみ
Eventually, a sorrow too big for two hands arrived there
叫びは高らかに慈しむほど
The cry is loud enough to be cherished
痛みは空よりも麗らかに
The pain is more serene than the sky
追想のディスペア
Reminiscence Despair
凍死して誰が笑う？ 染まる 嘆く 抱く 叫ぶ
Who laughs in freezing death? Staining, grieving, embracing, screaming
透明で目に見えない 意識 言葉 不安 未来
Transparent and invisible consciousness, words, anxiety, future
忌袋 暗記 まぎるの凶器は
The dread bag, memorization, the weapon that cuts through is...
口元が不自然に引き攣ったまま
With the mouth unnaturally twitching
おいで おいでされたら最後 サヨナラもう癒えず
If you're called to come, that's the end, goodbye, no longer healing
目が合えば速い呼吸になる
If our eyes meet, my breathing quickens
追想のディスペア
Tsuisou no Despair
打ち疲れた
I'm tired of hitting
この鼓動は 無力で儚いもの
This heartbeat is helpless and fleeting
冷たく引き千切るような
Like being torn apart coldly
僅かな残像
A slight afterimage
そして海に落ち込んだ
And then I fell into the sea
箱詰めの苦痛と
Packed with pain and
放物線を描く
Drawing a parabola
赤い軌跡は
The red trajectory is
最上の祭りに彩られ
Adorned with the finest festival
追想のディスペア
Reminiscent Despair
まるで闇に描かれた
As if drawn in the darkness
叶わない夢模様
A dream pattern that won't come true
髪を振り乱すような
Like shaking out my hair
気配がざわめく
A presence rustles
やがてそこに訪れた
Before long, it arrived there
両手に余る悲しみ
Sorrow that overflows from both hands
叫びは高らかに慈しむほど
The scream is so loud that it's cherished
痛みは空よりも鮮やかに
The pain is more vivid than the sky
追想のディスペア
Reminiscent Despair
Yellow Yellow HAPPY
作詞：CHAKI/ポケットビスケッツ
Lyrics: CHAKI/Pocket Biscuits
作曲：パッパラー河合
Composition: Pappala Kawai
もしも 生まれ変わっても
Even if I'm reborn
また私に生まれたい
I want to be born as myself again
この体とこの色で
With this body and this color
生き抜いてきたんだから
Because I've lived through it
いつか 太陽が消えて
Before the sun disappears someday
なくなる前に
And is gone
もっと あなたを好きなこと
I must tell you more
伝えなくちゃ
How much I love you
欲張りな私
I'm greedy
好きになったのなら
If I've fallen in love with you
完璧に
Perfectly
あなたを捕まえてみたい
I want to catch you
あなたの細胞
Your cells
少しも残さず
Without leaving a single one
盗まなきゃ
I must steal them
満足しないのよ
Or I won't be satisfied
うまくいかないほど
The more things don't go well
やりがいがあるわ
The more it's worth it
恋も夢も食べまくって
Devouring love and dreams
叶えられるよ きっと
I can make them come true, surely
もしも 生まれ変わっても
Even if I'm reborn
また私に生まれたい
I want to be born as myself again
この体とこの色で
With this body and this color
生き抜いてきたんだから
Because I've lived through it
いつか 太陽が消えて
Before the sun disappears someday
なくなる前に
And is gone
もっと あなたを好きなこと
I must tell you more
伝えなくちゃ
How much I love you
許されるための
For the sake of being forgiven
ずるいいたずらも
Even the sly pranks
やり尽くして
I've done them all
たどり着いた性格も
Even the personality I've ended up with
黄色い映画に
You laugh and say it's like
出てるみたいだと笑うけど
I'm in a yellow movie
羨ましがってる
But you're actually envious
リアルはいつも
Reality is always
嘘の中にある
Inside a lie
誰も本当のことなんて
No one will tell you
教えてくれない
The truth
だから あなたを泣かせる力が
So if I have the power to make you cry
あれば笑わす力
I also have the power to make you laugh
...なも あると信じているのよ
...believe that it exists too
小さな 小さな 魔法を甘く
Sweetly, a tiny, tiny magic
狂わせる 薬なんて いらないの
I don't need a drug that makes me go crazy
みんな 不幸なふりをしているだけなの
Everyone is just pretending to be unhappy
みんな 欲しがるお金で
With the money that everyone wants
黄色い子犬を買った
I bought a yellow puppy
みんな 欲しがる幸せ
The happiness that everyone wants
強く 強く 抱きしめた
I hugged it tightly, tightly
もしも 生まれ変わっても
Even if I were to be reborn
また 私に生まれたい
I want to be born as myself again
この体とこの心で
With this body and this heart
生き抜いてきたんだから
Because I've survived through it all
すべては 私が私でいるために
Everything is so that I can be myself
すべては すべては
Everything, everything
ハッピーのために
is for happiness
太陽が 消えてなくなる前に
Before the sun disappears
もっと あなたを好きなこと 伝えなくちゃ
I must tell you more that I love you
はーい！ということで！
Yes! So!
うわー！後ろの圧が凄かったー！
Whoa! The pressure from behind was incredible!
はーい！ということでですね、お聴きいただきました！
Yes! So, you've just heard...
声枯れたわ...
My voice is gone...
大丈夫ですかお二人とも？
Are you two okay?
肩痛いわ...
My shoulders hurt...
腱鞘炎になりそうだわ
I feel like I'm getting tendonitis
すごい弾いてたよ、二人とも！
You both were playing so hard!
ということで、一旦楽器には消えていただきましょうかね。
So, let's have the instruments disappear for a bit.
はい、ポン！消えろー！
Yes, poof! Begone!
はい、なくなりましたー
And they're gone!
ということでですね、絶望ビリー、まず最初に聴いていただきましたけども、お二人めちゃめちゃカッコよかった！
So, we first heard 'Zetsubou Billy', and you two were incredibly cool!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
凄い良かったよ！え、誰が選曲したんだい？これ。
It was so good! Hey, who picked this song?
これは、え、でもなんか、私かな？私かな？
That was, well, I think it was me? Me?
そうだね。
That's right.
ふーりあが出したら、わためも知ってたんだよね。
When Flare suggested it, Watame knew it too.
そう、知ってた。好きな曲！
Yes, I knew it. I love that song!
そう、だから意外だったの。
Right, so it was a surprise.
一緒に歌えて嬉しかった！ありがとう！
I was happy to sing it together! Thank you!
こちらこそー！
Likewise!
いやー、良かったよー！なかなかお二人で歌うことあんまり...
Man, it was great! You two don't usually sing together much...
意外と、確かにないね。
Surprisingly, we really don't.
やろうよ、もっと！
Let's do it more!
ね、もっとやろう！
Yeah, let's do more!
もっと歌ってくださいよ、お願いしますよ！
Please sing more, I'm asking you!
そしてフブちゃんは！
And as for Fubu-chan!
はい、私はですね、Yellow Yellow Happyという曲を歌わせていただきました！
Yes, I sang a song called 'Yellow Yellow Happy'!
知ってる人は知っている曲でございます！
It's a song those in the know will know!
はーい！
Yes!
お二人ともね、ちょっととあるポジションとしてね、今回いていただきまして。
And you two were there in a certain position this time.
かき鳴らしていただきましたけども、どうでした？
You were strumming away, but how was it?
サビの圧が凄いのよ、後ろの！
The pressure in the chorus was intense, from the back!
歌いながらちょっと笑わないように必死やった。
I was trying so hard not to laugh while singing.
こんなんなってた...
I was going like this...
めちゃめちゃ踊ってたもんな！
You were really dancing!
目立ってなんぼ！
It's all about standing out!
サビ出し凄かったよ！恐ろしかったね、後ろ！
The chorus entry was amazing! It was terrifying back there!
でも可愛かったね！
But it was cute!
いや、でも良かった、良かったです。ありがとうございました。
Well, it was good, really good. Thank you.
こちらこそー！
Likewise!
でもなんか途中、犬だなと思ってなかった？
But didn't you think I was a dog at one point?
あ、そう！あの、「みんな欲しがるお金で、黄色い角巻を買った」って...
Oh, right! That part, 'With the money everyone wants, I bought a yellow Tsunomaki'...
黄色い綿飴を買ったー！
I bought a yellow cotton candy!
犬じゃねーよ！
It's not a puppy!
出荷ってこと？ドナドナってこと？
Does that mean you're being shipped? Like 'Dona Dona'?
出荷すっか...
Shall I get shipped...
韻踏んでんじゃねーよ！
Stop with the rhyming!
ねー、いや本当に楽しかったです！
Man, it really was fun!
これで終わり？
Is this the end?
え、まだあるよねー！
Wait, there's more, right?!
次のデュエットは... おっと、私と...
The next duet is... oh, it's me and...
羊！
The sheep!
はーい！エルフ出荷されてきまーす！
Okay! Elf is being shipped off!
バイバイバーイ！頑張ってね！
Bye-bye-bye! Good luck!
はーい！頑張るよー！
Yeah! We'll do our best!
巡り巡る 君を辿る
Round and round, tracing you
僕の探す 全てになった
You became everything I was looking for
剥がれ落ちる 心が知ってた
My peeling heart knew
愛してる
I love you
この空の下で二人
Under this sky, the two of us
ゆらりゆらりまた風に吹かれ
Swaying, swaying, blown by the wind again
身を寄せ合ってゆく
Drawing closer together
ROLL
作詞・作曲：岡野昭仁
Lyrics & Composition: Akihito Okano
大きな時の流れの中で
Within the flow of vast time
僕は
I...
何を手にしたんだろう
...what have I gotten my hands on?
目も摘みに集め咲かせたものを
The things I gathered and made bloom without picking the buds
すぐに枯らせてしまう
Soon wither away
雲は風に流されどこかで消える
Clouds are carried by the wind and disappear somewhere
あるがままで生きようとするあまりそれさえも
Trying so hard to live as they are, that even that...
見えない
...can't be seen
巡り巡る君を辿る
Going around and around, tracing you
僕の探すすべてになった
You became everything I was searching for
剥がれ落ちる心が知ってた
My peeling-away heart knew it
愛してる
I love you
この空の下で二人
Under this sky, the two of us
ゆらりゆらりまた風に吹かれ
Swaying, swaying, blown by the wind again
身を寄せ合ってゆく
Drawing closer together
独りよがりの愛情は君に届かずに彷徨った
Self-satisfied love wandered without reaching you
分かり合えるはずの君が遠くて
You, whom I should have been able to understand, are far away
強くうねる行き場のないこの苛立ちだけ
Only this strongly surging frustration with nowhere to go
投げた
I threw it
巡り巡る僕は迷う
Going around and around, I am lost
君にとって足りないもの
What you're missing
剥がれ落ちる心に沁みて
Piercing my peeling-away heart
痛み出した
It began to ache
締めつける空の色と
With the color of the tightening sky
頬を伝う君の涙だけ
And only your tears streaming down your cheeks
目に焼きつく
Burned into my eyes
君に触れ
Touching you
君を抱き
Holding you
温もりや呼吸を感じ
Feeling your warmth and breath
二人の合言葉 知り
Knowing our secret password
手にしたと信じてた
I believed I had it in my hands
だけど今 君の中
But now, inside of you
苦しみや悲しみに
To the suffering and sadness
触れてしまった
I have touched
気付いてしまった
I have noticed
僕はそれを恐れてたんだ
I was afraid of that
巡り巡る君を辿る
Going around and around, tracing you
僕がすべて抱いてあげる
I will embrace everything
そしてここに二人で集め
And gathering here together
咲かせよう
Let's make it bloom
名も知らぬ花でもいい
Even an unknown flower is fine
枯れぬように優しく包んで
Wrapping it gently so it won't wither
ずっと咲かせる
I'll make it bloom forever
約束の星
作詞：うらん 作詞：大久保薫
Yakusoku no Hoshi
Lyrics: Uran Composition: Kaoru Okubo
君がいる 心それだけで...
You are here, with that alone in my heart...
君がいる 心 それだけで
You are here in my heart, and with just that,
絡みつく 闇も 光へと
even the entangling darkness turns to light.
約束の 星を 抱きしめて
Embracing the promised star,
飛び立とう 今 輝きへと
let's take flight now, towards the radiance.
あの日の 空が 残した
What the sky left behind on that day,
笑顔の スケッチ
is a sketch of smiles.
胸の奥で 溢れたんだ
Overflowing deep within my chest,
こんな あたたかい 涙
are these warm tears.
初めてだよ
It's the first time for me.
勇気に変えて 歩いていこう
Turning them into courage, let's walk on.
時の 風に 包まれ
Enveloped by the winds of time,
切なく 舞う サヨナラ
a sorrowful "goodbye" dances in the air.
いつか また 出会えるよね
We'll be able to meet again someday, right?
遠き 空に 約束
A promise to the distant sky.
君がいる 心 それだけで
You are here in my heart, and with just that,
絡みつく 闇も 光へと
even the entangling darkness turns to light.
もう二度と 迷わないよ
I won't lose my way ever again.
たとえ 雨が 降り続いていても
Even if the rain continues to fall,
見つめたい あの 雲の行方
I want to watch the path of those clouds.
追いかけて その先へ行こう
Let's chase them and go beyond.
約束の 星を 抱きしめて
Embracing the promised star,
飛び立とう 今 輝きへと
let's take flight now, towards the radiance.
新しい 靴が 痛くて
My new shoes are painful,
立ち止まってしまう こともあるけどね
and there are times when I stop in my tracks.
気まぐれ 雲に 差し込む
Shining through the whimsical clouds,
夢の粒を
grains of dreams.
そっと集めて 描いていこう
Let's gently collect them and paint our future.
いつも 強がることで
By always putting on a brave face,
強くなろうとした
I tried to become strong.
足りないところがあるから
Because there are parts of me that are lacking,
明日が生まれてくるんだね
tomorrow is born, isn't it?
君がいる 遠く離れても
You are here, even if we are far apart.
こんなにも 側にある 気持ち
This feeling is so close to me.
もう一度 出会う その日まで
Until the day we meet once more,
とっておきの 自分 見つけよう
I'll find the best version of myself.
忘れない 大切に触れた
I won't forget the preciousness I touched,
かけがえのない あの 一秒
that irreplaceable second.
約束の 星に 導かれ
Guided by the promised star,
続く道を 歩いていく
I'll walk the path that continues.
君がいる 遠く離れても
You are here, even if we are far apart.
こんなにも 側にある 気持ち
This feeling is so close to me.
もう一度 出会う その日まで
Until the day we meet once more,
とっておきの 自分 見つけたい
I want to find the best version of myself.
忘れない 大切に触れた
I won't forget the preciousness I touched,
かけがえのない あの 一秒
that irreplaceable second.
約束の 星に 導かれ
Guided by the promised star,
続く道を 歩いてゆけ
Go forth on the path that continues.
君がいる
You are here.
約束の星
Star of Promise
君がいる〜
...because you are here.
わ〜！
Whoa!
君がっ！
You!
わ〜！
Whoa!
僕がっ！
I!
いるっ！
Are here!
ということで
And with that,
君たちがいるよ！
You guys are here!
おっと、私たちがいる！
Oh, we are here!
私たちがいる〜！
We are here!
そして私がいる！
And I am here!
みんなもいる！みんなもいる！
Everyone is here! Everyone is here!
これがバカタレ！
This is Bakatare!
バカタレ！バカタレ！
Bakatare! Bakatare!
ぽこぽこ、ぽこドゥン！
Poko poko, poko-dum!
バカタレ〜！
Bakatare!
はい！ということで２曲聴いていただきました。
Yes! So, you've just heard two songs.
まずは、白上とわためで
First, by Shirakami and Watame,
「ROLL」！
"ROLL"!
いや、よかったね。なんかノリノリでしたね、さっき。
Man, that was good. You guys were really grooving earlier.
ポルノ歌うの実は
Singing Porno Graffitti is actually...
そう、初めてなの、キツネさん、ポルノを。
Yeah, it's my first time, Mr. Fox, singing Porno.
初めて！そうなんですよ。
First time! That's right.
いやいや、その初めてをいただきました。
No, no, I got to share that first time with you.
キツネさん、最高だったね、キツネさん。
Mr. Fox, it was the best, wasn't it?
あとちょっとね、いい感じに...あれ、何、ちょっとのけもの？
And just a little bit... wait, what, am I being left out?
ちょっと待って！わ、わ、わ、はい、入ります！
Wait a minute! Wa, wa, wa, okay, I'm coming in!
あ、あ、挟まった、そんな！離してよ！
Ah, ah, I'm sandwiched! Oh no! Let go of me!
ということでね、ポルノ、選曲させていただきました。
So, I chose Porno Graffitti for our song selection.
すっごい良かった！
It was so good!
ありがとう。いや、何曲にしようかすごい悩んで。
Thank you. Man, I really struggled with which song to pick.
わためだからポルノ歌いたいなと思ってて。
Since it's Watame, I wanted to sing Porno.
最初は、メリッサとかドラマティックいっとくかと思ったんだけど。
At first, I thought about going with "Melissa" or "Dramatic".
かっこいいよね、そっちも。
Those are cool too, right?
でもね、なんかこののんびりした曲も欲しいなと思って。
But I felt like having this more laid-back song too.
「ROLL」にしました。
So I went with "ROLL".
ナイス選曲！
Nice choice!
白上が一番好きな曲です、「ROLL」は。
"ROLL" is Fubuki's favorite song.
あ、そうなの！？
Oh, really!?
そうなんだよ、一番好きな曲をちょっとね、歌わせていただきやした。
That's right, I got to sing my absolute favorite song.
すごい良かった！ありがとう！
It was so good! Thank you!
ポルノ他にもいっぱい聴きたいな。
I want to hear more Porno Graffitti songs.
あ、３人でいく？やろうよ！
Oh, shall we do it with all three of us? Let's do it!
キミガ〜 カンジル〜 カンジル〜
You... feel... feel...
そんな曲じゃないんですよ！
That's not how the song goes!
やだなぁ、ネオメロドラマティック。
Oh, come on, "Neo-Melo Dramatic".
ポルノ３人になってしまった、ハルイチです。
We've become a Porno trio, I'm Haruichi.
ジョバイロもいこう、ジョバイロ！
Let's do "Joibairo" too, "Joibairo"!
昔のポルノのジョバイロ、ジョバイロ！
Classic Porno's "Joibairo", "Joibairo"!
ポルノ縛りやる？ポルノ縛りライブやるべ！
Should we do a Porno-only set? Let's do a Porno-only live!
やろう！わため、何がいい？ポルノの曲。
Let's! Watame, what do you want? Which Porno song?
え〜何がいいかな、選べないんだよなぁ〜。
Hmm, what should I pick? I can't choose~.
アポロ、アポロ、アポロいっとく？アポロ！
"Apollo", "Apollo", should we go with "Apollo"? "Apollo"!
ボクラノ〜
Our~
そんな低くない、ナカオカ低いよね。
It's not that low, Nakaoka's voice is low, isn't it?
ウマレテクル〜
Born into this world~
またみんなでやろうよ、やりましょう、またポルノ縛りも。
Let's do it with everyone again. Let's do a Porno-only session too.
やりたいですな〜。
I'd love to do that~.
そしてそして、フレアの曲が、これはなんの曲なんだい？
And, and, Flare's song, what song is this?
これは「ガッシュ」の挿入歌です。
This is an insert song from "Gash Bell".
「ガッシュ」の挿入歌！「約束の星」。
A "Gash Bell" insert song! "Star of Promise".
綺麗だったよ〜！めちゃめちゃ綺麗だった。
It was beautiful! It was so, so beautiful.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
出だし以外は綺麗だった！
It was beautiful except for the beginning!
なんで！なんでこれやっちゃったのかなぁ。
Why! Why did I do that?
なんか、バタバタバタってなってきたから、やったほうがいいのかなって。
It felt like things were getting hectic, so I thought I should do something.
やだ、そしたら私もイエロー・イエロー・ハッピーでこうやって入ってきたよ。
Oh man, then I should have come in like this with "Yellow Yellow Happy".
確かに！ねぇ、あと１歩早かったね。
True! Just one step faster, right?
ジャ、ジャ、バン！「君がいる〜」って。
Ja, ja, bang! "Because you are here~"
あれかっこよかったよ！キレッキレだった、もうドヤ顔だったね。
That was cool! You were so sharp, you had such a smug look.
キレッキレだったね。
It was really sharp.
そう、すごかったよ。痺れたぜ。
Yeah, it was amazing. It gave me chills.
はい！ということでね、じゃあ次の曲もありますので。
Yes! So, since we have more songs to come...
そろそろ準備しましょうか。はい！
...shall we start getting ready? Yes!
では、準備いくぞ、はけるぞ〜！
Okay, let's get ready, we're heading off!
どっち、こっち、こっち。あ、どっちでもいいよ。
Which way? This way, this way. Oh, either way is fine.
どっちでもいいんかい！
You're saying either way is fine!?
英雄
Hero
格好つけてるつもりで 得意になって
Thinking you're cool, getting all full of yourself
大事なことは全部 置き去りにしちゃって
Leaving everything important behind
自分で自分を苦しめている秀才
A genius making themselves suffer
そんな僕にサヨナラ さあ トランスフォーム
Say goodbye to that me, now, transform
闇が怖くてどうする
What will you do, being afraid of the dark?
あいつが怖くてどうする
What will you do, being afraid of that guy?
足踏みしてるだけじゃ 進まない
Just treading water won't get you anywhere
男なら 誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, become strong for someone else
歯を食いしばって
Grit your teeth
思い切り守り抜け
And protect them with all your might
転んでもいいよ
It's okay to fall down
また立ち上がればいい
Just stand back up again
ただそれだけ できれば 英雄さ
If you can just do that, you're a hero
アウェイ！
Away!
今日もなんだか やる気が起きないなんて
Saying you're just not feeling motivated again today
甘え通しの自分が 本当は嫌いで
Actually hating how much you baby yourself
とりあえずは表で 深呼吸個室
For now, go outside and take a deep breath
そんじゃ今からしましょうか Transformation
So, shall we transform now? Transformation
弱気になって震える　明日の君はどうする？
When you're feeling weak and trembling,
what will the you of tomorrow do?
黙って下向いてちゃ聞こえない
If you're silent and looking down, I can't hear you.
男なら　誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, be strong for someone else's sake.
ぶつかり合って精一杯やってみろ
Clash with each other and give it your all.
泣いてもいいよ　また笑えればいい
It's okay to cry, as long as you can laugh again.
ただそれだけできれば　英雄さ
If you can do just that, you're a hero.
男なら　誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, be strong for someone else's sake.
歯がゆくて見てるだけじゃ始まらない
It's frustrating just watching,
nothing will start.
これが正しいって言える勇気があればいい
As long as you have the courage to say
"this is right".
ただそれだけできれば　英雄さ
If you can do just that, you're a hero.
男なら　誰かのために強くなれ
If you're a man, be strong for someone else's sake.
歯を食いしばって思いっきり守り抜け
Grit your teeth and protect to the very end.
転んでもいいよ　また立ち上がればいい
It's okay to fall down,
as long as you can stand up again.
ただそれだけできれば　英雄さ
If you can do just that, you're a hero.
Alright!
はー！ということで！
Haa! And with that!
いやあ、暴れた！
Wow, we really let loose!
Thank you! Thank you! Arigatou!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
てかみんなギターかい！
I mean, everyone had guitars!
ギターなんだよ！
They're guitars!
三本ギターかい！
Three guitars!
いい感じにこう、写真撮ってみる？
Should we, like, try to take a nice photo?
いいじゃん！ガールズバンド感かっこいい！
Nice! The girls' band vibe is cool!
ガールズバンド感いいよ！
The girls' band vibe is good!
俺がギターだ！
I'm the guitar!
俺もギターだ！
I'm the guitar too!
じゃあベースのつもりだ！
Then I'll pretend to be the bass!
じゃベース！見たベース！もっと！
Then bass! Look, a bass! More!
はい、それじゃギター消えろ！ポイ！ポイ！ポイ！
Okay, now guitars, disappear! Pop! Pop! Pop!
ということで、「英雄」でございました！
And so, that was 'Eiyuu'!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
いや、楽しかったね「英雄」。
Man, 'Eiyuu' was fun.
気持ちいいね！
It felt great!
いや、よかったよ。「Alright」がすごいみんなでできてよかったと思います。
Yeah, it was good. I think it was great
that we could all do the "Alright" together.
はい！はい！ということで...
Yes! Yes! And with that...
なんと！
Behold!
これで終わりなのー？
Is this the end?
えー？もし終わりなのー？
Eh? Is it already over?
まだあるよね？まだあるよね？
There's still more, right?
次が最後の曲？
Is the next one the last song?
ってことはさ、こういうのってさ、普段はさ、ここで告知とかあるんじゃないの？
Which means, usually in these things, aren't
there announcements or something here?
あ！告知！告知！ない！
Ah! Announcements! Announcements!
There are none!
ないんかい！
There aren't any?!
残念！ありません！
Too bad! There aren't any!
なんもないんかい！
There's nothing at all?!
今はないけども、また今後、バカタレあるでしょう色々と！
There aren't any right now, but there will be
more for Bakatare in the future, surely!
なんかあったっけ？
Was there something?
おいおいおい！俺俺俺！
Hey, hey, hey! Me, me, me!
え？覚えてないけど...
Eh? I don't remember...
え？耳あるよな？長い耳ついとるよな？ふわふわのついとるよな？
Eh? You have ears, right? Long ears?
Fluffy ones?
でもあの、あれだね。これからもね、二人ともよろしくお願いします。
But, well, from now on too, I look forward
to working with both of you.
あ、よろしくお願いいたします！
Ah, I look forward to working with you too!
なんで他人行儀なんだよ！
Why are you being so formal?!
え？ビジネスフレンドなの？
Eh? Are we business friends?
やだ！これからもビジネスとして仲良くやっていくんで、今後ともよろしくお願いします！
No! We'll continue to get along well as business
partners, so I look forward to working with you!
じゃあビジネスの心構えで...
Then with a business mindset...
いや、そんなことないで！
No, that's not true!
みんなときゃ無理って言うね！
Everyone says it's impossible to keep it
strictly business!
だま... あと一曲！
Shut... One more song!
あと一曲でございます！
There is one song left!
もうこれでちょっとMCパートが終わっちゃうので、最後に一言ずつちょっと感想もらおうかな？
With this, the MC part is almost over, so maybe
we could get a few words from each of you?
じゃあわためからいいかい？今日のバカタレライブどうでしたか？
Shall we start with Watame?
How was today's Bakatare Live?
え！何も考えてなかった！
Eh! I didn't think of anything!
何も考えずにやってたか！
You were doing it without thinking?!
でもやっぱ音楽っていいよね！
But as I thought, music is great, isn't it?
楽しかったもー！これからもやろうでもっと！
It was so fun! Let's do more from now on!
やろうね！やろうね！
Let's! Let's!
じゃあ続いてフレア！
Next, Flare!
何も考えてなかったけど、
I didn't think of anything either, but...
やっぱ私たちって「歌ってみた」をやりたくて集まったところもあって...
After all, we gathered because we wanted
to do song covers...
で、みんな歌が好きなメンバーで集まっているのでね、これからもいっぱい歌とかも歌いたいね。
And we've gathered as members who love
singing, so I want to sing many more songs.
歌いたいね！
I want to!
すごい今日楽しかったし、これからも一緒に歌っていこうね。
I had a lot of fun today, so let's
keep singing together from now on.
フブキちゃん感想聞かせて！
Fubuki-chan, tell us your thoughts!
はいはいはいはい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
ま、本日ね、バカタレ2周年ということで、
Well, since today is Bakatare's 2nd anniversary,
なんとも2年も連れ添っていた...
and we've been together for two years...
ま、こうやってライブができて本当に良かったよ！
I'm really glad we could do a live performance like this!
またね、来年3周年とかもライブとか
I hope we can do another live for our 3rd anniversary next year
何かしらね、出来たらいいなと思っております！
or something like that!
今日ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
はい、じゃあ最後の楽曲、じゃあちょっと...
Alright, then for the last song, let's...
ま、最後まででもね、やっぱり我々バカタレ、
But even until the very end, as Bakatare,
クライマックスしてこうぜ！
let's keep it at the climax!
そうだね！
That's right!
もうクライマックスまでね、もうちょっとありますね！
There's still a bit more until the climax!
ということで、次は...
So, next is...
お！いいじゃん！
Oh! Nice!
ジャンプしちゃう？ジャンプ！
Shall we jump? Jump!
ジャンプしちゃう？お！
Shall we jump? Oh!
ジャンプ！
Jump!
ジャンプして終わりました！
We finished with a jump!
じゃあちょっと準備してきまーす！
Alright, we'll go get ready!
時間の波をつかまえて
Catching the wave of time
今すぐにゆこう 約束の場所
Let's go right now to the promised place
限界無限 いざ飛び込め
Limitless, infinite, dive in now
Climax Jump!
Climax Jump
作詞：藤林 聖子 作曲：鳴瀬 シュウヘイ
Lyrics: Shoko Fujibayashi / Composition: Shuhei Naruse
いーじゃん！いーじゃん！すげーじゃん！
Nice! Nice! Amazing!
叶えたい夢があるなら
If there's a dream you want to come true
信じなくちゃ 願った日々を
You have to believe in the days you wished for
Catch the wave
迷いそうなとき必ず
Whenever you feel like getting lost
想いの強さが導く
The strength of your feelings will guide you
君が望む未来すでに
The future you desire is already
In your hands
始まりはいつも突然
The beginning is always sudden
運命を連れてゆく Time-trippin' ride
A Time-trippin' ride that takes fate with it
不可能を超えて掴み取るさ
Transcend the impossible and grasp it
Climax!
変わることを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of change
明日の自分見失うだけ
You'll only lose sight of your future self
誰より高い空へとぼうぜ
Let's fly to a sky higher than anyone else's
Climax Jump!
いーじゃん！いーじゃん！すげーじゃん！
Nice! Nice! Amazing!
胸の中 みんなひそやかに
Inside everyone's hearts, secretly
書き換えたい記憶もある
There are memories they want to rewrite
Memory
新しい朝を待つなら
If you're waiting for a new morning
今を塗り替えろそこから
Rewrite the present from there
ほんの少し勇気を持って
With just a little bit of courage
In your mind
旅立ちはいつも必然
Departure is always inevitable
どうせなら飛び回れ Time-trippin' ride
If so, fly around on a Time-trippin' ride
探し出すのさ 自分だけの
Find your very own
Climax!
昨日までの記憶すべて
All the memories up until yesterday
必要とわかる日が来るはず
The day will come when you realize they're necessary
誇れるようにさらなる Climax Jump!
To be proud, a further Climax Jump!
心は強くする 大事な言葉とか
Important words that make your heart strong
かけがえない思い出を集めて
Gathering irreplaceable memories
もう少しあと少し 届かない星空
Just a little more, a bit more, to the starry sky
あきらめたら そこが終着
If you give up, that's the end
さあ...
Now...
始まりはいつも突然
The beginning is always sudden
運命を連れてゆく Time-trippin' ride
A Time-trippin' ride that takes fate with it
不可能を超えて掴み取るさ
Transcend the impossible and grasp it
Climax!
変わることを恐れないで
Don't be afraid of change
明日の自分見失うだけ
You'll only lose sight of your future self
誰より高く
Higher than anyone else
昨日より高く
Higher than yesterday
Climax Jump!
いーじゃん！いーじゃん！すげーじゃん！
Nice! Nice! Amazing!
おわり
The End